[Music]
hello and welcome to what's new in
projects and service management we
continue our investment into the
industry specific areas of business
Central you already know that we are
adding integration to Dynamics 365 field
service and the business Central and the
service management model people usually
developers who are using Insider build
all already noticed some rare
architecture happening in the internals
of service management where we are
transforming it to behave like IV
solution and use the same patterns and
dependencies but we also continue to
polish project and service management
functionality to align it with other
parts of
application and in this video I would
like to focus on exactly this
part let's start with project management
area we continue our journey related to
up taking of Rich warehouse and
inventory capabilities and now we are
also supporting locations where directed
put away and PE is enabled we also added
extra capability to do replenishment for
projects in addition to planning
worksheet or order planning
capabilities we also getting some uh
features developed by Community via Cod
development contribution and this one of
the example extend the text we also did
number of UI alignments all the way
let's start with the demo let's navigate
to the project list I'm now in the
project manager rolling Center and when
I mentioned U improvements you probably
expect me to mention that we are adding
more columns here not this time this
time we are adding more actions and for
example we are adding project we cockpit
action right to the project list this
functionality is quite powerful and
useful if you're dealing with work in
progress for projects and because it's a
little bit hidden not everybody knows
about it existence for example it allows
you to delete work in progress entries
which allows you to change the viip
method in the project and try a
different one
right but this is existing functionality
getting closer what else available here
not on the main menu because usually
we're trying to add actions but do not
promote them unless it's
necessary uh it will give you choice to
actually use personalization
capabilities to pin what is needed let's
for example go to the project assembly
orders you remember that in previous
release we deed assembly to order
capability and you can navigate to
assembly from cardart now from the list
as well but what else we can see here we
can also see Warehouse capabilities and
let's take a look at the peak lines yeah
what what do we see here Warehouse PE
lines because somebody probably me
already created Warehouse Peak for this
project and what do we see here we see
here a white location and for people who
working with business Central for a long
time already know the synonym of white
location as location where the most uh
comprehensive or Advanced Warehouse
capabilities enabled it's directed put
away and
pick so it's enabled for this location
and now you can use it for project as
well you can see that project
consumption will work as Warehouse Peak
mandatory all right let's navigate to
the warehouse Peak document and register
it to make sure that it actually works
as expected all right so we completed
the peck let's open the document and
explore uh internally what's happening
with this
project all right the first project task
where you can see is a location and
being selected right there or which can
be defaulted to different values that's
something we added earlier now let's
navigate to the project planning lines
and we can see here project planning
line yeah with the element which we can
transfer to the uh project Journal
because now we want to you perform
consumption of it or actually register
usage okay it is transferred now let's
let's open it and it is here we can post
it we will not post it we will do
posting preview feature my favorite ones
uh because we can see the results
without actual changing data in the
database all right project Ledger entry
is here value entry is here Warehouse
entry is also here for white location
where we
consuming uh picked items what if I will
go and change quantity from two which
was originally picked to let's say
five expected yeah because we didn't
pick five we picked only two and this is
exactly what uh business Central tells
us about all right so that was about
directed Peck and put away support we
have one limitation still pending we
will talk about it in uh later stage
today the next one is extended text you
can see how I call it let's open it in
the different mode introduced in the
previous release but you know we do
multi-release enhancements now we have
project task and we can see the item
here let's scroll to the right a little
bit item semi-automatic two pieces and
we can see new function insert extended
text added by Vi code development
project all right I will press the
button and what we can see extend the
text was added we can of course
configure it to be automatically
inserted for projects or for invoices or
whatever document you like so you can
configure different ones for different
purposes why do we need
those to be able to
print Let's uh navigate to print sent
and choose preview project quote let's
use a
preview and uh Zoom a little
bit now you can see that text is also
printed on the quote thank you for
contributing next element will be about
replenishment you know that we already
have assembly to order to build right
for the project you can also use
planning worksheet with most advanced
planning capabilities or order planning
uh for order per order execution but
sometimes people would like to do
planning from the project right away
that's why we will go to the project
planning lines see what we have here and
I have here remote pump and power cord
which are needed both in quantity 10 and
then I have new action hiding very well
under the actions functions and very
bottom it actually behaves very similar
to what we already know in the sales
order document it goes through the
content and it analyze
availability uh what can be used
and suggest to buy what is missing and
you can see that it suggest to buy 10
and eight why eight because guess we
already have something available or on
its way actually and then we have two
extra ways how to create purchase
documents this is a big difference
comparing to uh sales area where it
actually doesn't matter if you reserve
or not it just adds reservation but here
the change will be noticeable I will
activate Reserve in one line but keep it
blank for another one and press
okay because both are purchased from the
same vendor we will get the same
purchase order uh on the screen and we
can scroll a little bit F further down
to see what is actually will be
purchased yeah both components will be
here quantity 10 and 8 as expected but
quantity reserved only for one line
which is fair because this is exactly
what we wanted to see but there is one
more difference and if I will scroll to
the right to the project number and
project task number which I made added
via personalization you can see that it
is populated only for the first line and
the second line doesn't have those which
is not a problem it's still reserved for
exactly that project so once I will
register
purchase which I will do right now you
can see there are three item Ledger
entries first
item F100 F100 is purchased and used for
the project immediately so it
immediately get consumed the second item
is only purchased and now it is in
inventory but it is reserved for
specific project so now you decide
actually how you want to process the
purchase document linked to the the
project
immediately uh register usage or do it
later the second mod is uh actually very
useful for warehouse integration because
we do not support Warehouse receipt
scenarios for projects it means if you
are using white location with directed
pick and putaway you cannot post
purchase via wherehouse receipt and
expect it to be immediate ly consumed
not yet at least all right so that's
what I wanted to tell you accept one
extra
thing all right I mentioned that we have
something available how do I know
that we also added item availabilities
in different places for example in
Project planning lines and project
journals let's look at the availability
by
event and expand it
and you can see that we have project and
two purchases with
quantity two and eight the eight is the
one which we created just a few minutes
ago okay we can also navigate to the
created purchase documents if you can
use uh related project planning lines
and purchase
lines okay this is the in case if it's
not reserved you can navigate to the
purchase lines this way to summarize
what has changed for projects ignoring
the like old journey by now because it
was multiple releases when we did
multiple improvements finally we get uh
directed put away and locations
supported we have a more convenient way
to do replenishment for projects and
user experience is like very much
aligned with what we saw in as
areas and now let's talk about service
management
it also gets ux
improvements obviously but we also
getting archiving capabilities which we
are missing in service area for service
quotes and orders we also added support
for report selection in one extra report
and uh we will talk about filing of
service contracts and quote contracts
which were available
before but now gets
improved all right now I'm in in the
service manager rolet Center and here we
will start with the service quote I will
open my list of service quotes here what
we see oh we can see the document
attachments actually looking very good
you can upload it right here so you
don't need to click this number anymore
but this is a generic Improvement you
already saw it in different places not a
service
specific of course if you're talking
about ux alignment and improvements
usually we mention the columns and yeah
we didn't
added columns in the projects area but
for service we could not control
ourselves and we added your reference
here as well in the majority of the list
so now you can find the right document
without opening the card all right what
next we will do we will do make order we
use this action to convert quote to
order this is a familiar confirmation
but now something new something new in
this service people who already used
purchase area or sales where you
converted sales quote to the sales order
or same for purchase you already know
about this
useful dialog which allows you to jump
directly to the newly created order we
can do that in the service as well this
feature is added via Cod development
project all right this is service order
which is uh right here let's do one
thing first let's AR arive
it yes do we want to Archive it of
course we do all right number of
archived versions here what do we do
next we will start changing it let's
delease this
line let's scroll down and find this
your reference and change it to
something absolutely
different all right what next probably
what next we will go to archived
versions
explored and we can see there is a
restore setion and of course we want to
try
it and the document has been
restored let's close everything uh
service quote and find our service order
of course we cannot restore the document
itself it will be closed so we need to
reopen it again
so yeah document attachment uh does it
look familiar yes now it again has two
lines and it has a old reference which
we mentioned form so what else do we
want to look here let's open
the Service item
worksheet and press print button
actually nothing suspicious here or
nothing new from the user perspective
you will not notice
change uh because it behaves the same
for new environment and for upgraded
environment but
if in your business it's needed to print
a different document now you can
navigate to the report selection service
and you can find the here a new line
with a item worksheet where you can
change uh
report maybe select different layout or
maybe you want to print several
documents at one
time all right so we now know how to do
archiving we know how to print service
uh item worksh Street uh what about
filing
uh actually for service contracts and
the service contract quote the archiving
functionality already existed it called
filing yeah let's open the service
contract quote and open it and you can
find here the button which is called
file contract quote okay let's press it
do you want to file it
yes all right the next step we will
convert quote to end order
we don't want to create invoices no all
good so here now we can find the service
contract quote here but we will not go
there probably people who work with the
filing capability they know its
limitations it actually didn't support
all fields which you expect or tables
which you expected to support but
also uh filed contract had a tendency to
be deleted uh together with the main
document but we stopped that let me show
to you so now if you go and search for
file service contracts yeah it's
actually the shareed one it can be for
quote and for contract as well you can
see the all filed uh versions even if
the quote doesn't exist anymore you can
explore what was in the original one and
you can see some related tables
here and comments there right how do we
do that we have some changes in the in
the settings let's navigate to the
service management setup and have a
quick look at what has happened
here in the contract part you can see
the new toggle deleted filed contracts
which is off so now filed versions of
the contract or contract quote will not
be deleted if you want ex uh old
Behavior you need to activate with
toggle back also for archiving we can
see the
familiar uh settings for quote where you
can actually decide if it will be always
question or never and for orders it's
like uh on or off uh setting very
similar to what we can see in the
purchase and sales areas
already uh again now we have contracts
files and of course the list can can be
uh big how to keep our database under
control the same story as usual
retention policies you can now add new
retention policy and
include uh filed service contract or
service header archive there or actually
both if necessary and then it will be
deleted as other retention policy
entries will be
processed now we know how to archive or
file contracts and orders how to change
report to be printed when you want to
print service item worksheet and also
minor uh usability experience uh changes
in the service Management
Area thank you for watching